A Guide to the Amaza Lee Meredith Papers, 1912, 1930-1938
Johnston Memorial Library, Virginia State University
Special Collections and Archives, Johnston Memorial Library, Virginia State University
Amaza Lee Meredith Papers, 1912, 1930-1938
Special Collections and Archives, Johnston Memorial Library, Virginia State University
1982-20
This collection contains ca. 5,000 pieces.
The Amaza Lee Meredith papers contain personal and business documents generated by Ms. Meredith which reflect the activities of her lifetime. Included are materials related to her career at Virginia State University, her participation in the V.S.U. Alumni Association the official records of the Azurest North Syndicate, and personal correspondence with several prominent blueprints, line drawings, and sketches of Ms. Meredith's designs which demonstrates her pursuits in architecture.
Administrative Information
Access
The items in Box 29 are restricted; there are no other restrictions in this collection.
Acquisition Information
These papers were given to the V.S.U. Archives/ Special Collections Department by decree of Ms. Meredith's Last Will and Testament.
Biographical/Historical Information
Amaza Lee Meredith was born in Lynchburg, Virginia on August 14,1895. She was the daughter of Emma P. Kenny (Meredith) and Samuel P. Meredith. She had two sisters and one brother; the eldest child, Maude, maintained a life-long closeness with Amaza. In 1915, Meredith completed here early schooling in Lynchburg, where she graduated at the top of her class.
Her First teaching job was at a rural ungraded school called Indian Rock, located in Botetourt County, Virginia. Here, Meredith organized the Indian Rock Parent- Teacher's Association, which worked in conjunction with the Negro Organization Society of Virginia to bring improvement to the local school system. In 1918, she returned to Lynchburg, where she taught elementary school. In 1922, she served as Valedictorian for her class at the Virginia Normal and Industrial Institute. This was followed by six years of teaching mathematics at Dunbar High School in Lynchburg.
Ms. Meredith enrolled in the Teacher's College of Columbia University, New York in 1928. It was there where she earned both her Bachelor's and Master's Degrees in Fine Arts Education.
Her career with Virginia State University began in 1930, though she took a leave of absence from 1934-35 to complete her Master's degree. In 1935, she advanced to the position of Department Char, where she remained until her retirement in 1958. Amaza Meredith established the schools of Fine Arts department.
Beyond her career at V. S. U., Meredith's life was also rich in contributions. Her artistic self spilled over into these other facets of her life. She exhibited her art at the Virginia Museum of Fine Arts and in galleries in New York and North Carolina. Some works were acquired by groups, such as the Gillfield Baptist Church, where they are still displayed; many others hang in the homes of area residents.
She also developed interior decorating and design skills. In the field of business, she coordinated color schemes for campus buildings. To provide for new shelving units, she created blueprints, which proposed modifications in the art department layouts.
This remarkable person also pursued architectural interests. Though she had no known formal training, Amaza Meredith fully designed her own home - both inside and out, and im1939, it was built on Boisseau Street here in Ettrick. She named it "Azurest South." In the ensuing decades, Meredith laid out the blueprints for several homes, most notably in Sag Harbor, Long Island, New York.
In the 1950's Sag Harbor flourished as resort area for blacks. Amaza and her sister, Maude, worked together to buy, create, and develop the subdivision later called "Azurest North." They worked with others to establish the "Azurest Syndicate, Inc." Syndicate lots were sold to individual investors, who the built summer, or year-round cottages and this land. Ms. Meredith designed at least two of these residences: 1) Terry Cottage, summer home for her sister, Maude Terry: and 2) Edendot, belonging to friends Ed and Dot Spaulding.
Additionally, Meredith provided several sets of blueprints for the proposed V. S. U. Alumni House in 1949. Once these plans fell through, Amaza tried another approach: She willed her half of Azurest South to the V. S. U. Alumni Association in the hopes that the dream for which she had worked so long would become a reality. Joint ownership of Azurest South was held with Ms. Edna Colson, another retired faculty member of V. S. U. In 1985, the Alumni Association purchased the Colson's half of the house, and Azurest South is now the official V. S. U. Alumni House.
Meredith was generally active in the Alumni Association. She was an honorary member of the Gillfield Baptist Church. While she participated in several other organizations and committees, the extent of her involvement is not known.
In 1984, Amaza Lee Meredith died.
Scope and Content Information
The Amaza Lee Meredith Papers, 1912-1983, document a slice of Virginia's history in the twentieth century. This founder of the Fine Arts Department lived a life abundant in contributions well beyond her career at Virginia State University, while some materials relate directly to her work as a faculty member. Her devotion to education spanned over four decades; these papers reflect her efforts. Born in 1895, Meredith was raised in a period which some consider the lowest point in African-American history since the antebellum era. A product of such adversity, she adjusted to work and achieve during and after a time of legal segregation. This collection speaks to her successes in overcoming the "obstacles" of both race and gender.
Beginning in 1930, Meredith corresponded frequently with family, most notably, her sister, Maude Terry. These letters reveal the depth of love and loyalty the family cultivated and nurtured for lifetime. They demonstrate the difference in women's roles between the black and white interdependent relationship with men; black women have received greater support from their peers in the arena of independence. In this vein, Meredith's family gave her nothing short of a full endorsement for her outstanding achievements. It is likely that such contributed to her ability to surmount societal resistance.
Many of Meredith's peers were educators. Her papers include correspondence with Helen Edmonds, Anne Crittendon Preston, and Jean Murrell Capers (who later made her mark in politics). The remaining correspondence comes from people of varied backgrounds, also as viable research material.
Another group of personal correspondence related to Stafford Evans, a prized students of Ms. Meredith. While there is some continuation of correspondence into the 1980s, most of these letters were written while Evans served in the navy from 1943-45. Included are copies of The Mananan, a WWII Black sailors' March and December of 1945. This sub-series lends expression to the ambiguity, which black soldiers felt while in fighting for a democracy to which they themselves were not privy.
Meredith's business records document the origins of the Azurest Syndicate in 1953. Ms. Meredith worked with her sister, Ms. Terry, to pioneer the development of a Black summer resort area known as the Azurest North. The Syndicate served to regulate the subdivision's lot sales. The unique aspect of this venture are numerous: the development of a black resort in this time period, the syndicate, and the project's creation and development by two Black women - whose careers were unrelated to such a field.
It appears that, from the 1950's through the 1970's some homes in Azurest North were designed by Ms. Meredith. Though she had no known formal architectural schooling, she created countless line and ink drawings as well as blueprints, which are also included in this collection. Several of these projects succeeded in being built. For many more, the end result is as yet undetermined.
Unquestionably, Meredith designed and built her own home, known as Azurest South, which she truly reflects her artistic gift. Blueprints, line drawings, and sketches of this home are available for research.
Found in another series are the plans for the proposed V. S. U. Alumni House. Beginning in 1949 and working through the next decade, Meredith was active with the Alumni House Committee in attempts to produce an Alumni House. She retained general Alumni records from as early as 1936 and ending in 1969.
Lastly, she created more than a dozen scrapbooks, devoting each to a different subject and/or person. They contain documents, photos, letters, news clippings, and ephemera, which combine to form a rich source of research on their topics. The materials cut across all the other sub-series in these collections.
Amaza Meredith maintained a life-long friendship with Edna Colson, former head of the Education Department at V. S. U. They also shared a residence and had mutual friends. Clearly, in order to research either person in- depth, it will be necessary to study the other. Some further correspondence exists in Colson/Hill the sub-series of MS. Colson's personal correspondence dating from 1905-79. This includes information of the trip to Europe made by Colson and Meredith. Some materials, however are restricted (Box 29).
Organization
Series I. BIOGRAPHICAL DATA (Container 1)
Series II. CORRESPONDENCE & REPORTS (Containers 1-9)
A. Family [1. By Date / 2. By Name]
B. Personal [1. By Name / 2. By Date]
C. Business [1. Azurest Syndicate / 2. U. S. Patent Office]
Series III. WORK- V.S.U. (Container 9)
Series IV. ALUMNI (Containers 10-12)
A. General
B. House Committee
Series V. ORGANIZATIONAL AFFILIATIONS (Container 12)
A. Dunbar High School Class Reunion
B. Gillfield Baptist Church
C. The Virginia Federation of Colored Women's Club
Series VI. SCRAPBOOKS (Containers 13-15, loose books)
Series VII. PHOTOGRAPHS (Container 16)
Series VIII PRINTED MATERIAL (Container 17)
Series IX. ARCHITECTURAL DRAWINGS (Containers 18-20)
A. Furniture
B. Line Drawings
C. Blueprints
Contents List
- BIOGRAPHICAL DATA
  - Biographical Data (Box-folder 1:1)
  - Obituaries (Box-folder 1:1a)
- CORRESPONDENCE & REPORTS
  - A. Family
    - Correspondence: Meredith-Family 1930-1935 (Box-folder 1:2)
    - Correspondence: Meredith-Family 1936 (Box-folder 1:3)
    - Correspondence: Meredith-Family (Box-folder 1:)
    - Correspondence: Meredith-Family 1937 (Box-folder 1:4)
    - Correspondence: Meredith-Family 1938 (Jan-Mar) (Box-folder 1:5)
    - Correspondence: Meredith-Family 1938 (April-June) (Box-folder 1:6)
    - Correspondence: Meredith-Family 1939-1942 (Box-folder 1:7)
    - Correspondence: Meredith-Family 1943 (Jan-June) (Box-folder 1:8)
    - Correspondence: Meredith-Family 1943 (July-Dec) (Box-folder 1:9)
    - Correspondence: Meredith-Family 1944 (Box-folder 1:10)
    - Correspondence: Meredith-Family 1945-1948 (Box-folder 1:11)
    - Correspondence: Meredith-Family 1949-1950 (Box-folder 1:12)
    - Correspondence: Meredith-Family 1951-1952 (Box-folder 1:13)
  - B. Personal
    - Correspondence: Meredith-Family 1953-54 (Box-folder 2:14)
    - Correspondence: Meredith-Family 1955-56 (Box-folder 2:15)
    - Correspondence: Meredith-Family 1957-60 (Box-folder 2:16)
    - Correspondence: Meredith-Family 1961 (Box-folder 2:17)
    - Correspondence: Meredith-Family 1962 (Box-folder 2:18)
    - Correspondence: Meredith-Family 1971-82 (Box-folder 2:19)
    - Correspondence: Meredith-Family n.d. (Box-folder 2:20)
    - Correspondence: Meredith-Family 1967 (Box-folder 2:20a)
    - Correspondence: Meredith-Family 1942 (Box-folder 2:20b)
    - Correspondence: Meredith-Family n.d. (Box-folder 2:21)
    - Bills & Receipts n.d. (Box-folder 2:21a)
    - Correspondence: Meredith/Jean Murrell Capers 1953 (Box-folder 2:22)
    - Correspondence: Meredith/Jean Murrell Capers 1954-55 (Box-folder 2:23)
    - Correspondence: Meredith/Jean Murrell Capers 1957-59, 1961-62 (Box-folder 2:24)
    - Correspondence: Meredith/Jean Murrell Capers 1967-69, 1971, 1974, 1976-77 (Box-folder 2:25)
    - Correspondence: Meredith/Jean Murrell Capers n.d. (Box-folder 2:26)
    - Correspondence: Meredith/Helen Cornele Cuyjet 1942-45 (Box-folder 3:26a)
    - Correspondence: Meredith/Helen Cornele Cuyjet 1946-52 (Box-folder 2:26b)
    - Correspondence: Meredith/Helen Cornele Cuyjet 1953,1982 (Box-folder 3:26c)
    - Correspondence: Meredith/Helen Cornele Cuyjet n.d. (Box-folder 3:26d)
    - Correspondence: Meredith/Helen Edmonds 1951 (Box-folder 3:27)
    - Correspondence: Meredith/Helen Edmonds 1952 (Box-folder 3:28)
    - Correspondence: Meredith/Helen Edmonds 1953(January-June) (Box-folder 3:29)
    - Correspondence: Meredith/Helen Edmonds 1953 (July-Dec) (Box-folder 3:30)
    - Correspondence: Meredith/Helen Edmonds 1954(January-September) (Box-folder 3:31)
    - Correspondence: Meredith/Helen Edmonds 1954(October-December) (Box-folder 3:32)
    - Correspondence: Meredith/Helen Edmonds 1956-57 (Box-folder 3:33)
    - Correspondence: Meredith/Helen Edmonds 1958-59 (Box-folder 3:34)
    - Correspondence: Meredith/Helen Edmonds 1960-61 (Box-folder 3:35)
    - Correspondence: Meredith/Helen Edmonds 1962, 1971, 1976, 1981 (Box-folder 3:36)
    - Correspondence: Meredith/Helen Edmonds n.d. (Box-folder 3:37)
    - Correspondence: Meredith/Stafford Ward Evans 1943 (June- September) (Box-folder 4:38)
    - Correspondence: Meredith/Stafford Ward Evans 1943 (October- December) (Box-folder 4:39)
    - Correspondence: Meredith/Stafford Ward Evans 1944(January- June) (Box-folder 4:40)
    - Correspondence: Meredith/Stafford Ward Evans 1944 (July- August) (Box-folder 4:41)
    - Correspondence: Meredith/Stafford Ward Evans 1944( September- December) (Box-folder 4:42)
    - Correspondence: Meredith/Stafford Ward Evans 1945 ( January- April) (Box-folder 4:43)
    - Correspondence: Meredith/Stafford Ward Evans 1945 ( May- July) (Box-folder 4:44)
    - Correspondence: Meredith/Stafford Ward Evans 1945 ( August- September) (Box-folder 4:45)
    - Correspondence: Meredith/Stafford Ward Evans 1945 ( October) (Box-folder 4:46)
    - Correspondence: Meredith/Stafford Ward Evans 1945 ( November- December) (Box-folder 4:47)
    - Correspondence: Meredith/Stafford Ward Evans 1946 (Box-folder 4:48)
    - Correspondence: Meredith/Stafford Ward Evans 1980-81 (Box-folder 4:49)
    - Correspondence: Meredith/U.S. Navy n.d. (Box-folder 4:)
    - Correspondence: The ManananMarch 3- June 17, 1945 (Box-folder 5:51)
    - Correspondence: The ManananJuly 4- December 13, 1945 (Box-folder 5:52)
    - Correspondence: Meredith/Florida Naomi Oettigrew 1977-78 (Box-folder 5:53)
    - Correspondence: Meredith/Mitchell 1951 (Box-folder 5:53a)
    - Correspondence: Meredith -- Personal 1930 (Box-folder 5:54)
    - Correspondence: Meredith -- Personal 1931 (Box-folder 5:55)
    - Correspondence: Meredith -- Personal 1932 (Box-folder 5:56)
    - Correspondence: Meredith -- Personal 1933 (Box-folder 5:57)
    - Correspondence: Meredith -- Personal 1934 (Box-folder 5:58)
    - Correspondence: Meredith -- Personal 1935 (Box-folder 5:59)
    - Correspondence: Meredith -- Personal 1936 (January- June) (Box-folder 5:60)
    - Correspondence: Meredith -- Personal 1936 (July - December) (Box-folder 5:61)
    - Correspondence: Meredith -- Personal 1937 (Box-folder 6:62)
    - Correspondence: Meredith -- Personal 1938 (Box-folder 6:63)
    - Correspondence: Meredith -- Personal 1939 (Box-folder 6:64)
    - Correspondence: Meredith -- Personal 1941 (Box-folder 6:65)
    - Correspondence: Meredith -- Personal 1942 (Box-folder 6:66)
    - Correspondence: Meredith -- Personal 1943 (January - September) (Box-folder 6:67)
    - Correspondence: Meredith -- Personal 1943 (October - December) (Box-folder 6:68)
    - Correspondence: Meredith -- Personal 1944 (Box-folder 6:69)
    - Correspondence: Meredith -- Personal 1945 (Box-folder 6:70)
    - Correspondence: Meredith -- Personal 1946 (Box-folder 6:71)
    - Correspondence: Meredith -- Personal 1947 (Box-folder 6:72)
    - Correspondence: Meredith -- Personal 1948 (Box-folder 6:73)
    - Correspondence: Meredith -- Personal 1949 (Box-folder 6:74)
    - Correspondence: Meredith -- Personal 1950 (Box-folder 6:75)
    - Correspondence: Meredith -- Personal 1951 (January - September) (Box-folder 6:76)
    - Correspondence: Meredith -- Personal 1952 (January - June) (Box-folder 6:77)
    - Correspondence: Meredith -- Personal 1952 (July - December) (Box-folder 6:78)
    - Correspondence: Meredith -- Personal 1953 (Box-folder 6:79)
    - Correspondence: Meredith -- Personal 1954 (Box-folder 6:80)
    - Correspondence: Meredith -- Personal 1955 (Box-folder 6:81)
    - Correspondence: Meredith -- Personal 1956 (January - June) (Box-folder 6:82)
    - Correspondence: Meredith -- Personal 1957 (Box-folder 7:84)
    - Study Tour n.d. (Box-folder 7:84a)
    - Study Abroad Tour n.d. (Box-folder 7:84b)
    - Correspondence: Meredith -- Personal 1958 (Box-folder 7:85)
    - Correspondence: Meredith -- Personal 1959 (Box-folder 7:86)
    - Correspondence: Meredith -- Personal 1960 (Box-folder 7:87)
    - Correspondence: Meredith -- Personal 1961 (Box-folder 7:88)
    - Correspondence: Meredith -- Personal 1962 (Box-folder 7:89)
    - Correspondence: Meredith -- Personal 1963-66 (Box-folder 7:90)
    - Correspondence: Meredith -- Personal 1967-70 (Box-folder 7:91)
    - Correspondence: Meredith -- Personal 1971-73 (Box-folder 7:92)
    - Correspondence: Meredith -- Personal 1975-76 (Box-folder 7:93)
    - Correspondence: Meredith -- Personal 1977 (Box-folder 7:94)
    - Correspondence: Meredith -- Personal 1979 (January - August) (Box-folder 7:95)
    - Correspondence: Meredith -- Personal 1979 (September - December) (Box-folder 7:96)
    - Correspondence: Meredith -- Personal 1980 (January - March) (Box-folder 8:97)
    - Correspondence: Meredith -- Personal 1980 (April- August) (Box-folder 8:98)
    - Correspondence: Meredith -- Personal 1980 (August - November) (Box-folder 8:99)
    - Correspondence: Meredith -- Personal 1980 (December) (Box-folder 8:100)
    - Correspondence: Meredith -- Personal 1981 (January - June) (Box-folder 8:101)
    - Correspondence: Meredith -- Personal 1981 (June- December) (Box-folder 8:102)
    - Correspondence: Meredith -- Personal 1982 (Box-folder 8:103)
    - Correspondence: Meredith -- Personal 1983 (Box-folder 8:104)
    - Correspondence: Meredith -- Personal n.d. (Box-folder 8:105)
    - Correspondence: Meredith -- Personal n.d. (Box-folder 8:106)
    - Correspondence: Meredith -- Personal n.d. (Box-folder 8:107)
    - Correspondence: Meredith -- Personal n.d. (Box-folder 8:108)
    - Correspondence: Meredith -- Personal n.d. (Box-folder 8:109)
    - Political n.d. (Box-folder 8:109a)
    - (Box-folder 9:)
  - D. Business
    - Azurest North Plat Map 1947 & 1948 (Box-folder 9:109b)
    - Azurest Syndicate, Inc. Correspondence 1953 (Box-folder 9:110)
    - 111 Azurest Syndicate, Inc. Annual Meetings (Minutes) n.d. (Box-folder 9:111)
    - 112 Azurest Syndicate, Inc. Reports n.d (Box-folder 9:112)
    - 113 Azurest Syndicate, Inc. Bank Statements n.d. (Box-folder 9:113)
    - Account- Meredith and Terry Azurest North n.d. (Box-folder 9:113a)
    - E. L. Parker Correspondence 1975 (Box-folder 9:113b)
    - E. L. Parker - House Plains Azurest North n.d. (Box-folder 9:113c)
    - Azurest Syndicate, Inc. Inventories n.d. (Box-folder 9:114)
    - U. S. Patent Office Golf Valet n.d. (Box-folder 9:115)
- SERIES III: WORKS-V.S.U.
  - Virginia State University Correspondence n.d. (Box-folder 9:116)
  - Virginia State University Art Department Lesson Plans, Reports n.d. (Box-folder 9:117)
  - Virginia State University Art Department n.d. (Box-folder 9:118)
  - Virginia State University Black Man in American Music n.d. (Box-folder 9:119)
  - Virginia State University Centennial Commission n.d. (Box-folder 9:120)
  - Virginia State University "Co-op" n.d. (Box-folder 9:121)
  - Virginia State University Federal Credit Union 1958-60 (Box-folder 9:122)
  - Virginia State University President's Address 1969 (Box-folder 9:123)
  - Virginia State University Professional 11-2-1934, 6-5-1958 (Box-folder 9:124)
  - Virginia State University Professional 03-24-1960,12-15-1976 (Box-folder 9:125)
  - 126 Virginia State University Professional 01-03-1977,03-07-1979 (Box-folder 9:126)
  - Virginia State University Student Movement 1968,1971 (Box-folder 9:127)
- SERIES IV: ALUMNI
  - A. General
    - Correspondence- Alumni- Constitution n.d. (Box-folder 10:128)
    - Correspondence - Alumni- Annual Report 1969 (Box-folder 10:129)
    - Correspondence - Alumni Annual Meeting Minutes 6-1-1968 (Box-folder 10:130)
    - Correspondence - Alumni-Executive Committee 1948-57, 1959-61 (Box-folder 10:131)
    - Correspondence -Alumni-Treasury Reports 1936-f.y. Ending 1954 (Box-folder 10:132)
    - (Box-folder 10:133)
    - Correspondence- Alumni- Treasury Reports 1955-56,1957-61,1971 (Box-folder 10:134)
    - Correspondence- Alumni- Receipts 1951,1958,1960-61 (Box-folder 10:135)
    - Correspondence- Alumni - Correspondence 1938, 1943, 1946, 1948 (Box-folder 10:136)
    - Correspondence - Alumni - Correspondence 1951-53 (Box-folder 10:137)
    - Correspondence - Alumni - Correspondence 1956-57, 1959 (Box-folder 10:138)
    - Correspondence- Alumni- Correspondence 1960-61, 1968, n.d. (Box-folder 10:139)
    - Correspondence- Alumni - Fine Arts Graduates 1937-60 (Box-folder 10:140)
    - Alumni Forms, Individual File Sheets Lists of Graduates n.d. (Box-folder 11:142)
    - Alumni Names: Alumni Others n.d. (Box-folder 11:143)
    - Alumni Notes 1957-59 (Box-folder 11:144)
    - Alumni Letters, Notes (Originals) 1945, 1949, 1959(May- Oct) (Box-folder 11:145)
    - Alumni Letters, Notes (Originals) 1959 (Nov-Dec) 1960 (Box-folder 11:146)
    - Alumni Letters, Notes (Originals) n.d. (Box-folder 11:147)
    - Alumni Scholarships (VSU) ca. 1951-53 (Box-folder 11:148)
    - Alumni - Songs n.d. (Box-folder 11:149)
    - Alumni Sub Committee: Dr Nicholas 1960 (Box-folder 11:150)
    - Alumni Sub Committee: Ovcerton- Johnson 1960 (Box-folder 11:151)
    - Alumni Summit/Sub-Committee 1950, 1953, 1959 (Box-folder 11:152)
    - Alumni Summit: Sub- Committee 1960, 1962, n.d. (Box-folder 11:153)
    - Alumni Testimonial n.d. (Box-folder 11:154)
    - Alumni-Printed Newsletters 1949-56 (Box-folder 11:155)
    - Alumni- Printed Newsletters 1957-63 (Box-folder 11:156)
    - Alumni - Printed Statesman May 1960 (Box-folder 12:157)
    - Alumni- Printed Brochures n.d. (Box-folder 12:158)
    - Alumni- Printed Bulletins, Ephemera n.d. (Box-folder 12:159)
    - (Box-folder 12:)
  - B. House Committee
    - Alumni- Printed Minutes (HC) 1959-60 (Box-folder 12:160)
    - Alumni-Printed Original House Fund 1959 (Box-folder 12:161)
    - Alumni-Printed Alumni House Fund Committee Organizational Material 1959 (Box-folder 12:162)
    - Alumni- Printed Alumni House Fund Committee Organization Material 1960 & n.d. (Box-folder 12:163)
    - Alumni-Printed Fund Committee 1949-50 (Box-folder 12:164)
    - Alumni-Printed Documents (Alumni House Fundraising) 1949-51, 1953-55, 1959 (Box-folder 12:165)
    - Alumni- Printed V. S. U. - Alumni House n.d. (Box-folder 12:166)
    - Alumni-Printed House Plans '-Alumni n.d. (Box-folder 12:167)
- SERIES V: ORGANIZATIONAL AFFILIATIONS
  - A. Dunbar High School Class Reunion
    - Meredith- Printed Personal Dunbar High School Class Reunion n.d. (Box-folder 12:168)
    - Meredith-Printed Personal Dunbar High School Class Reunion n.d. (Box-folder 12:169)
  - B. Gillfield Baptist Church
    - Meredith - Printed Personal Gillfield File n.d. (Box-folder 12:170)
    - Meredith - Printed Personal Art Exhibit-Sale Gillfield Baptist Church n.d. (Box-folder 12:171)
  - C. Virginia Federation of Colored Women's Clubs